在这个讲座中，我想要做的是谈论机器人末端执行器的速度。
In this lecture, what I want to do is talk about the velocity of the robot's end-effector.
所以在最后几个讲座中，我们研究了前向运动学和前进等概念
So the last couple of lectures, we have looked at concepts like forward kinematics and forward
运动学是关节角度与机器人末端执行器之间的关系
kinematics is the relationship between the joint angles and the robot's end-effector
姿势，所以我放入关节角度，然后我走出末端效应器的姿势。
pose, so I put in the joint angles and I get out the end-effector pose.
反向运动学恰恰相反。我说我希望末端效应器摆出姿势
The inverse kinematics is sort of the opposite. I say what I want the end-effector pose to
是为了实现我需要的关节角度算法的结果
be and what comes out of the algorithm of the joint angles that I need in order to achieve
那个末端效应器的姿势。
that end-effector pose.
问题是，我们将在这个特定的讲座中讨论的是速度变换。
The problem, what we are going to talk about in this particular lecture is velocity transform.
如果关节以这个特定的速度移动，那么机器人的末端执行器的速度是多少
If the joints move at this particular velocity, what is the velocity of the robot's end-effector
并且你注意到我已经将关节的速度写成q点，所以点代表
and you note that I have written the velocity of the joints as q-dot, so dot represents
时间变化率。它是微分学中常见的符号和姿势
the time rate of change. It is a common notation in differential calculus and the pose of the
机器人的末端执行器我一直用这个符号psiE来表示姿势
robot's end-effector I have been using this symbol, psi E, to represent the pose of the
终末效应者，我们已经谈到了这是如何组合位置和方向。
end-effector and we have talked about how that is combination of position and orientation.
因此，在这种特殊情况下，我们现在谈论的是余弦点。我们正在谈论
So, in this particular case, what we are talking about now is cosine dot. We are talking about
姿势的变化率，这是一个有趣的，不一定是直观的
the rate of change of a pose and that is an interesting and not necessarily intuitive
事情;所以首先我们要讨论姿势的变化率
thing; so first of all we are going to talk about what does the rate of change of a pose
意思是，我们用什么样的数学对象来表示那个，然后是什么
mean, what kind of mathematical object do we use to represent that and then what is
那个东西，psi点和关节角度的变化率之间的关系
the relationship between that thing, the psi dot, and the rate of change of the joint angles
机器人本身。
of the robot itself.
所以，这就是本讲座的内容。它是关于理解之间的关系
So, that is what this lecture is about. It is about understanding relationship between
关节速度和姿势变化率。
velocity of the joints and the rate of change of pose.